SUSHMA V

Certified Blockchain developer with 5+ years of experience with Master's degree focused in Computer Science and Information Security assurance from Manipal Institute of Technology. Experienced in developing Decentralised Blockchain applications using Hyperledger Fabric and Ethereum. Competent in cloud platforms (AWS and Azure) and DevOps. Seasoned Full Stack developer with experience leading a team of back-end and front-end developers.

KEY SKILLS

Blockchain: Hyperledger Fabric, Ethereum, Solidity

Front End: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript/ES6, jQuery, Angular, AJAX, XML, JSON

Back End: JAVA, Node.js, Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Hibernate

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

Cloud: AWS, Azure

DevOps: CI/CD, Jenkins, Docker **Testing**: Chai, Mocha, JUnit

HONORS AND AWARDS

- Second runner up for Cybervein Blockchain Hackathon held on 28-April-2019.
- Excellence award for application RICOH Rewards and Recognitions.

WORK HISTORY

Tech Lead April 2019 - Present

Digitectura Technologies Private Limited

Technologies/Platforms:

JAVA, Spring Boot, Kafka, MySQL, Microsoft Azure, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular, Bootstrap, AmCharts

Responsibilities:

- Requirement collection, designing and documenting the architecture with various design diagrams and database design.
- · Solely set up the workflow for the team software installations, GitHub, demo projects for the work flow.
- Single handedly created the front end application from the scratch and the backbone frontend components.
- Spring Boot REST end point with Kafka SASL and OAuth functionality.
- Solely deployed the code to Azure cloud and documenting the process and guidelines for the team.

Senior Full Stack Engineer

July-2018 - October 2018

Unifize

Technologies/Platforms:

Clojure, PostgreSQL, Swagger, Sentry

Responsibilities:

- · Database designing, writing stored procedures.
- REST end point with Clojure and integrating those with Swagger API documentation.
- · Integrate Sentry for error tracking in the application for different environments.

Full Stack Engineer

Taylor And Francis

February 2017 - June 2018

Technologies/Platforms:

JAVA, Spring boot, Node.js, MongoDB, AngularJS Schema Form, CI/CD, Docker, AWS, Jenkins, Terraform, Mocha, Chai, JUnit, Sentry, Swagger, New Relic, Neo4J

Responsibilities:

- · Writing REST end points for different Microservices using Spring Boot and Node.js Express.
- · Writing test cases for Spring Boot API using JUnit.
- Development of frontend application using AngularJS.
- Writing test cases for Node is using Mocha Chai. Configure Karma test runner on Angular JS application.
- · Understand and using the CI/CD pipeline involving Jenkins, GitHub, Docker, AWS, Terraform.
- · Containerising the micro services using Docker and deploy them on AWS.
- · Integration of New Relic APM tool for the monitoring and management of the application performance.
- · Integration of Sentry for error tracking in the application for different environments.

Web Developer

July 2015 - July 2016

Ricoh Innovations

Technologies/Platforms:

Java, Spring MVC, HTML, CSS, JS, ¡Query, MongoDB, Mocha, Chai

Responsibilities:

- Requirement collection, designing and documenting the architecture with various design diagrams and database design.
- Single handedly handled full stack development, testing, hosting application on RICOH private cloud and documentation of the entire process.

Java Developer

July 2012 - August 2014

Dell International Services

Technologies/Platforms:

JAVA, JSP, Spring MVC, Hibernate, MySQL, JSF

Responsibilities:

- · Creating frontend for a portal using JSF.
- Creating spring MVC application with Hibernate and MySQL.
- · Deployment of the application and fixing the deployment issues.

EDUCATION

International Institute of Information Technology Bangalore

PG Certification in Blockchain Technology, June 2020

GPA: #todo out of #todo

Manipal Institute of Technology, Manipal

Master of Technology, Computer Science and Information Security, June 2016

GPA: 7.8 out of 10

Siddaganga Institute of Technology, Tumakuru

Bachelor of Engineer, Computer Science, July 2012

GPA: 7.8 out of 10